# DEREK A. SHAIN

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

## CONTACT

208-606-2581

derek0anthony@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/derekshain

https://github.com/DerekShain

#### PROFILE

A software developer with the ability to learn new technologies in a fast paced environment. Experienced in front and back-end development. Efficient and effective lead/supervisor able to produce under pressure as proven over in five years of military service and in the civilian workforce. Commended for tactful, professional, and efficient communication skills at all levels of management. Seeking an opportunity with Allata to expand my knowledge and growth and help develop the future.

## SKILLS

- HTML/CSS
- Bootstrap
- JavaScript
- Vue.js
- Node.js
- MySQL
- MongoDB
- Mongoose
- C#/ .Net
- Scrum

## APPLICATIONS

#### **MYST**

- Gaming Social Media site with current news and live streams
- Full Stack Developer, UI/UX design
- Vue, NodeJS, JS, SCSS, MongoDb

#### **SPRINTR**

- Scrum Management
- Full Stack Developer, UI/UX design
- Vue, JS, MongoDb

#### THE NETWORK

- Social media platform to connect with friends
- Developer
- · Vue, HerokuApp API, Javascript

## EDUCATION

#### CodeWorks (2021)

- Fullstack Software Development

## Treasure Valley Community College 2020-Present

-- Fixed Wing Aviation program

## **United States Military Education** (2015)

- ·Navy War College
- ·Community College of the Airforce

#### EXPERIENCE

## Software Development Student CodeWorks 08/2021-11/2021

- Learned Javascript ES6, NodeJs, SQL, Vue, Agile/Scrum processes,
   Backend and front end development, and the value of integrating security
- Utilized scrum processes to build multiple applications efficiently and effectively
- Multiple application development with MVC, multiple API's, custom design through the use of Figma, security with Auth0, online storage with Google Firebase, and database hosting with MongoDB

## Product Flow Specialist Best Buy 10/2020 - Current

- Assisted customers with questions on upcoming new products and services to include drone laws and regulations and Windows 11 deployment.
- Received and shipped items as needed, ensure floor has appropriate level of stock items
- Assisted with processing online orders, maintained knowledge of hundreds of different products to stay up to date on current trends.

#### Receiving/Manifest Lead CTI Foods 12/2019-10/2020

- Oversaw receiving and other warehouse processes and lead 8 personnel to make sure work meets quality standards and is performed according to established procedures.
- Assist with the development, revision and enforcement of inventory management and procedures including record keeping, work instructions, ISO procedures, and other standard operational and work practices as necessary.
- Implemented a new way to track incoming and current inventory while developing a manifesting position through months of research utilizing Tableau and other systems.
- Continue to grow lean knowledge and use the tools to identify and assist with continuous improvement.